<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en, es"><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.3">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://francandon.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><link href="https://francandon.github.io/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en, es"/><updated>2024-09-12T15:54:23+00:00</updated><id>https://francandon.github.io/feed.xml</id><title type="html">blank</title><subtitle>Francisco Rodríguez Candón&apos;s personal website, featuring research insights, academic publications, and professional projects in Astrophysics. </subtitle><entry><title type="html">The Dark Matter Search</title><link href="https://francandon.github.io/blog/2024/formatting-and-links/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Dark Matter Search"/><published>2024-09-12T11:40:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-09-12T11:40:00+00:00</updated><id>https://francandon.github.io/blog/2024/formatting-and-links</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://francandon.github.io/blog/2024/formatting-and-links/"><![CDATA[<h2>Unveiling the Mysteries of Dark Matter and Dark Energy in Modern Astrophysics</h2> <p>Our knowledge of cosmic physics is vast and diverse, covering countless fields of research—from the subatomic particles that make up the Standard Model to the colossal structures of the universe. However, the deeper we delve into the fundamental workings of the cosmos, the more questions these advancements leave us with.</p> <p>In modern astrophysics, two major mysteries captivate the scientific community: the problems of <em>dark matter</em> and <em>dark energy</em>. These issues arise from discrepancies between astronomical observations of mass and energy in various galactic and extragalactic systems and the predictions derived from the theory of general relativity. These discrepancies suggest: 1) the presence of undetected dark matter-energy, 2) our current understanding of gravity is incorrect at these scales, or 3) a combination of both.</p> <p>Extensive experimental evidence supports the first option. This begins with mass discrepancies observed in the rotational curves of spiral galaxies [Rubin, 1980], extends to studies of anisotropies in the Cosmic Microwave Background (CMB) [Hinshaw et al., 2013], and includes analyses of Type II supernovae. Currently, this cosmological paradigm, known as the <span style="font-family: 'Times New Roman', serif;">&Lambda;</span>CDM model, is the most widely accepted by the scientific community. It posits the existence of a dark component to the universe's total mass and energy: <span style="font-family: 'Times New Roman', serif;">&Lambda;</span> represents the cosmological constant (dark energy), while CDM stands for Cold Dark Matter, referring to non-relativistic dark matter.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="science"/><category term="Dark"/><category term="Matter"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Dark Matter is one of the most intriguing topics in Physics, yet Unkown]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Google Gemini updates: Flash 1.5, Gemma 2 and Project Astra</title><link href="https://francandon.github.io/blog/2024/google-gemini-updates-flash-15-gemma-2-and-project-astra/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Google Gemini updates: Flash 1.5, Gemma 2 and Project Astra"/><published>2024-05-14T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-05-14T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://francandon.github.io/blog/2024/google-gemini-updates-flash-15-gemma-2-and-project-astra</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://francandon.github.io/blog/2024/google-gemini-updates-flash-15-gemma-2-and-project-astra/"><![CDATA[]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[We’re sharing updates across our Gemini family of models and a glimpse of Project Astra, our vision for the future of AI assistants.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Displaying External Posts on Your al-folio Blog</title><link href="https://francandon.github.io/blog/2022/displaying-external-posts-on-your-al-folio-blog/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Displaying External Posts on Your al-folio Blog"/><published>2022-04-23T23:20:09+00:00</published><updated>2022-04-23T23:20:09+00:00</updated><id>https://francandon.github.io/blog/2022/displaying-external-posts-on-your-al-folio-blog</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://francandon.github.io/blog/2022/displaying-external-posts-on-your-al-folio-blog/"><![CDATA[]]></content><author><name></name></author></entry><entry><title type="html">Master in Phyisics of the Universe</title><link href="https://francandon.github.io/blog/2020/twitter/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Master in Phyisics of the Universe"/><published>2020-09-28T15:12:00+00:00</published><updated>2020-09-28T15:12:00+00:00</updated><id>https://francandon.github.io/blog/2020/twitter</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://francandon.github.io/blog/2020/twitter/"><![CDATA[<p>During my stay at University of Zaragoza, I created together with my friend Miguel several videos for the CAPA social media. One of them was a promotional video for the Physics of the Universe master’s program. The number of people enrolled during that year had been very low, so we decided to promote the Master interviewing former students as myself. We recorded the video in the courtyard of the Faculty of Science, a beutiful day of March</p> <h1 id="promotional-video">Promotional Video</h1> <div class="jekyll-twitter-plugin"><blockquote class="twitter-tweet"><p lang="es" dir="ltr">¿Tienes pensado cursar estudios de Máster? 🎓<br/><br/>Si te interesa la cosmología, la astrofísica, la física de partículas, de astropartículas, de altas energías... <br/>El Máster en Física del Universo de la Universidad de Zaragoza es tu sitio, ¡te lo explicamos! <a href="https://t.co/GHWJpF4nzo">https://t.co/GHWJpF4nzo</a> <a href="https://t.co/OTrdghdUYE">pic.twitter.com/OTrdghdUYE</a></p>&mdash; CAPA (@CAPAUnizar) <a href="https://twitter.com/CAPAUnizar/status/1770748836954120688?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">March 21, 2024</a></blockquote> <script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script> </div>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="social-media"/><category term="X"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[I directed and edited the video presentation of the Physics of the Universe master's program.]]></summary></entry></feed>